♪Wind♪
♪ الرياح ♪
♪Incidentally blows away fascinating whispers of love♪
♪ يضرب عرضا بيادق الحب الرائعة ♪
♪Whispers of love♪
♪ حراس الحب ♪
♪Sound the best with loyalty to the only valentine♪
♪ دق أفضل بالولاء إلى الوصية الوحيدة ♪
♪The prosperous life♪
♪ الحياة المزدهرة ♪
♪Is when we are together all year round♪
♪ هو عندما نكون معا على مدار السنة ♪
♪For the rest of my life♪
♪ لبقية حياتي ♪
♪All I want is a perfect love with you♪
♪ كل ما أريد هو حبك المثالي ♪
♪I'll remain elegant for you all my life♪
♪ سأبقى أنيقة لك طوال حياتي ♪
♪Giving you my love little by little♪
♪ إعطائك حبي شيئًا فشيئًا ♪
♪I care for you with every piece of my heart♪
♪ أنا أهتم بك في كل قلبي ♪
♪And I miss you every day and night♪
♪ وأنا أشتاق إليك كل ليلة ♪
♪I'll be loyal to you in the best years of my life♪
♪ سأكون مخلصا لك في أفضل سنوات حياتي ♪
♪Melting love with gentle smiles♪
♪ تميّز الحب بالأعمدة الحمقاء ♪
♪I won't be afraid of anything♪
♪ لن أشعر بالخوف من أي شيء ♪
♪And I won't change my heart for you♪
♪ لن أغيّر قلبي من أجلك ♪
=Jade's Fateful Love=
= حب اليشم المؤلم =
=Episode 10=
= الحلقة 10 =
Your Grace, what are you thinking?
غريسك، ماذا تفكر؟
On the painting day, someone must have sneaked in
في يوم اللوحة، لا بد أن أحدهم تسخر
and stolen the account book.
وسرق دفتر الحساب
Account book?
دفتر الحساب؟
No wonder he said he would leave in advance.
لا عجب أنه قال إنه سيغادر مسبقًا
That was just an excuse.
كان ذلك مجرد عذر
Actually, he didn't leave.
في الحقيقة، لم يغادر
He sneaked in and stole the account book.
تسرق دفتر الحساب وسرقه
That day, we had Mr. Siyuan,
في ذلك اليوم، كان لدينا السيد سيوان
Miss Su Nian,
الآنسة سو نيان
Miss Lingxi,
الآنسة لينغشي
- and... - The South Prince.
- و... - الأمير الثالث
It must be him, the evil guy.
لا بد أنه هو، الرجل الشرير
I won't let him get in here again.
لن أسمح له بالدخول إلى هنا مجددًا
The... The South Prince?
الأمير الجنوبي؟
Brother, I'm innocent!
أخي، أنا بريء!
Brother, if you don't come to see me,
يا أخي، إذا لم تأتي لرؤيتي
I'll have to kill myself for innocence.
سأضطر إلى قتل نفسي للبراءة
Your Majesty, it's the South Prince.
جلالتك، إنه الأمير الجنوبي
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو
- don't do this. - Don't touch me.
- لا تفعل ذلك - لا تلمسني
- Your Highness. - Don't get me up.
- الأمير - لا تنهضي
Stay off. Let me die.
ابق هنا دعني أموت
- His Highness hasn't recovered. - Brother, come out and see me.
- الأمير لم يتعافى - أخي، اخرج وأرى
What is he doing here?
ماذا يفعل هنا؟
Brother.
أخ
Get him in.
استدعاه
Yes.
نعم
Greetings, Brother.
تحياتي يا أخي
There's no need of that here.
لا حاجة لذلك هنا
You're injured.
أنت مصابة
You can be seated.
يمكنكم الجلوس
My... my hips.
خلفيتي
I'd rather not sit.
أفضّل ألا أجلس
Zhixuan, you're here even before you recover.
زيشوان، أنت هنا حتى قبل أن تتعافي
What on earth do you want?
ماذا تريدين بحق السماء؟
I just don't understand.
أنا فقط لا أفهم
Zhou Shiyu's crime must be
يجب أن تكون جريمة تشو شي يو
more serious than mine, right?
أكثر خطورة مني، أليس كذلك؟
Brother, why did you punish him so little?
يا أخي، لماذا عاقبته بهذه الدرجة؟
So, you think I'm unfair?
إذن، هل تظن أنني غير عادل؟
I dare not.
أنا لا أجرؤ
I know
أعرف
I'm the concubine's son
أنا ابن محظية
while Shiyu is the lineal son.
في حين أن شيو هو ابن الإسقاط
But I think you should punish him impartially.
لكنني أعتقد أنه يجب أن تعاقبوه بنزاهة
We shouldn't be punished the same way.
لا ينبغي أن يُعاقب بنفس الطريقة
Otherwise,
خلاف ذلك
I'll have to...
سأضطر...
Your Majesty!
جلالتك!
I'm fine.
أنا بخير
I...
أنا...
I didn't mean to offend you, Brother.
لم أقصد أن أسأت إليك يا أخي
Zhixuan,
شيشوان
I actually care the same
في الحقيقة أنني أهتم بنفس
for you and Shiyu.
لك ولشيو
You're like my arms.
أنت مثل ذراعيّ
Even if you make mistakes,
حتى لو ارتكبت أخطاء
how do I have the nerve to break my arms?
كيف يمكنني كسر ذراعيّ؟
Brother,
أخي
do you really not think less of me
ألا تفكري بأقل مني حقًا
because I'm the concubine's son?
لأنني ابن محظية؟
I don't, of course.
بالطبع لا أفعل
Whatever Shiyu has,
مهما كان شيو
you always have it, too.
لديك كل شيء أيضًا
That's because I am...
هذا لأنني...
As good as Zhou Shiyu.
جيد مثل تشو شيوي
But in this case,
ولكن في هذه الحالة
Zhou Shiyu made a more serious mistake.
ارتكب تشو شيوي خطأ أكثر جسامة
Brother, if you don't change your mind,
يا أخي، إذا لم تغير رأيك
I'm not leaving.
لن أغادر
Even if I can't remonstrate with my life,
حتى لو لم أستطع الوقوف على حياتي
I'll keep remonstrating every day.
سأستمر في التنديد كل يوم
Then I'll have Shiyu go to Liuzhou for disaster relief.
إذن سأطلب من شيو الذهاب إلى ليوتشو للإغاثة من الكوارث
He'll atone for his crime.
سيتكسل عن جريمته
What do you think, Zhixuan?
ما رأيك يا Zhixuan؟
That's more like it.
هذا أحسن
Your Highness, you look much happier.
صاحب السمو، تبدو أكثر سعادة بكثير
Did you make it?
هل حققتها؟
Oh, Your Highness.
يا صاحب السمو
Xu,
شو
I should give you a big reward.
يجب أن أعطيك مكافأة كبيرة
Zhou Shiyu is expelled to Liuzhou.
تم طرد تشو شي يو إلى ليوتشو
Go tell the chefs
اذهب وأخبر الطهاة
to make more dishes for dinner.
لصنع المزيد من الأطباق لتناول العشاء
Tonight, I'll celebrate it.
الليلة، سنحتفل به
Liuzhou?
ليوتشو؟
Your Grace, is anything bothering you?
غريسك، هل أي شيء يزعجك؟
Mr. Perfect, you're hyper-informed.
السيد برفكت، أنت على دراية كبيرة
Do you know where I can buy the Boost Healing Powder?
هل تعرف أين يمكنني شراء مسحوق شفاء البوست؟
The Boost Healing Powder?
مسحوق غسل الأموال؟
Some special powder from Dongyu.
بعض المساحيق الخاصة من دونغيو
It perfectly heals the wounds.
إنه يشفى الجروح تمامًا
Your Grace, are you wounded?
هل أنت مصاب يا غريسك؟
Not me.
ليس أنا
But a friend of mine.
بل صديق لي
If it's something special from Dongyu,
إذا كان شيئًا مميزًا من دونغيو
I guess it's only available on the West Market.
أظن أنه متاح فقط في السوق الغربية
The West Market?
السوق الغربية؟
Su Nian, that silly prince is here again.
سو نيان، ذلك الأمير السخيف هنا مرة أخرى
Tell him I'm sick
أخبره أنني مريضة
and I'm not seeing anyone today.
ولا أواعد أحدًا اليوم
You won't see him?
ألن تريه؟
We don't have a new mission, anyway.
ليست لدينا مهمة جديدة على أي حال
It's quite fun to tease him.
مضايقته ممتع جدًا
We got the account book.
حصلنا على دفتر الحساب
There's no need to practice martial arts.
لا داعي لممارسة فنون الدفاع عن النفس
Su Nian, have you picked a weapon?
سو نيان، هل اخترت سلاحا؟
There he is.
ها هو ذا
Next,
التالي
I'll teach you how to use a weapon.
سأعلمك كيفية استخدام سلاح
No need.
لا حاجة
So, you've picked a weapon you want.
لذا، اخترت سلاحًا تريدينه
Show me what you picked.
أرني ما اخترته
(A Record of Miscellaneous Performing Arts)
(سجل الفنون التمثيلية المتنوعة)
I mean I'm not going to learn martial arts.
أعني أنني لن أتعلم فنون الدفاع عن النفس
You are not?
أنت لست كذلك؟
Why?
لماذا؟
Mr. Xingyi,
السيد شينغ يي
I really don't have a talent for martial arts.
ليس لدي حقا موهبة لفنون الدفاع عن النفس
Besides, you and I have only known for a few days.
إلى جانب ذلك، لقد عرفت أنا وأنت منذ أيام قليلة فقط
You don't need to bother like this.
لا داعي للقلق بهذا الشكل
You have no talent,
لا تملك الموهبة
but you can practice hard.
لكن يمكنك التدرب بجد
Don't worry about it.
لا تقلق بشأن ذلك
- I'll teach you. - Mr. Xingyi.
- سأعلمك - السيد شينغ يي
I'm tired.
أنا متعب
Do yourself a favor and leave.
قم بتقديم خدمة وغادر لنفسك
Su Nian.
سو نيان
Su Nian, but...
سو، لكن...
(Pleasant and Harmonious)
(النبل والانسجام)
Your Highness, did you see Her Highness?
صاحبة السمو، هل رأيت صاحبة السمو؟
Still hasn't come back?
ألم تعد بعد؟
You visited her three times.
زارتها ثلاث مرات
Will you keep waiting?
هل ستنتظر؟
No.
لا
I have to leave before it gets dark.
يجب أن أغادر قبل أن يصبح مظلما
How's the packing going?
كيف تسير التعبئة؟
It's done.
انتهينا
Your Highness, you always know.
صاحبة السمو، أنت تعرف دائما
His Majesty really sent you to Liuzhou
جلالة الإمبراطور أرسلك حقا إلى ليوتشو
for the disaster relief.
للإغاثة في الكوارث
Pack the ointment Yueling gave me.
احزم لي المرهم يويه
That ointment isn't very effective.
ذلك المرهم ليس فعالا جدا
I don't think it'll help a lot.
لا أعتقد أنها ستساعدنا كثيرًا
Why don't we take the miracle ointment
لماذا لا نأخذ مرهم المعجزة
Princess Luoyi gave you?
أعطيتك الأميرة لوي؟
Take the one from Yueling.
خذ واحدة من يويلينغ
Fine.
حسنا
(The West Market)
(السوق الغربية)
This is the West Market.
هذه هي السوق الغربية
Fried Spicy Chicken. Shish kebab.
مطعم حريف صديق، شيش كيباب
This place looks a little bit deserted.
يبدو أن هذا المكان مهجور بعض الشيء
Are you sure the powder is available here?
هل أنت متأكدة من أن المسحوق متوفر هنا؟
Fried Spicy Chicken. Shish kebab.
مطعم حريف صديق، شش كيباب
Delicious and loveable.
لذيذ ومحفوف
What do you want, sir?
ماذا تريد يا سيدي؟
Pick as you wish.
اختاري كما يحلو لك
This is good medicine from Dongyu.
هذا طبيب جيد من دونغيو
How about the Boost Healing Powder for wounds?
ماذا عن مسحوق شفاء بو للجروح؟
Sure.
بالطبع
Five taels of silver for one bottle.
خمسة تايل من الفضة لزجاجة واحدة
Pay before you get it.
ادفع قبل أن تحصل عليه
The set price for everyone.
السعر المحدد للجميع
This is the rule in the West Market.
هذه هي القاعدة في السوق الغربية
Quite a weird rule.
قاعدة غريبة تماما
Qianqian.
تشيان
(The Boost Healing Powder)
(مسحوق شفاء البوت)
Fried Spicy Chicken. Shish kebab.
مطعم حار جدا، شيش كيباب
This is it.
هذا هو الحال
(The Boost Healing Powder)
(مسحوق الشفاء)
(The North Prince's Mansion)
(قصر الأمير الشمالي)
Great. I've finally bought it.
رائع، لقد اشتريتها أخيرا
♪Telling what is awfully bothering♪
♪ تعيين ما يزعج كثيرا ♪
(The North Prince's Mansion)
(حفل الأمير الشمالي)
♪Ceaseless, love lingers and lingers♪
♪ لا يتوقف، الحب المستمر والثابت ♪
♪You and I both know it♪
♪ أنا وأنت نعرف ذلك ♪
(The North Prince's Mansion)
(قصر الأمير الشمالي)
Shiyu,
شييو
I bought you our special Boost Healing Powder.
اشتريت لك مسحوق تضميد الجراح الخاص بنا
Her Highness, you're back.
صاحبة السمو، لقد عدت
Where's His Highness?
أين صاحب السمو؟
His Highness has gone to Liuzhou.
لقد ذهب سموه إلى ليوتشو
(The Boost Healing Powder)
(مسحوق الشفاء)
Your Highness, before His Highness left,
صاحب السمو، قبل أن يغادر سموه
he asked me to take your orders.
طلب مني أن أطلب أوامرك
So, if you need anything, let me know.
لذلك، إذا كنت بحاجة إلى أي شيء، أعلميني
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو
if you want some food, drinks,
إذا كنت تريد بعض الطعام أو المشروبات
toys, or daily supplies,
أو اللوازم اليومية
tell me about it.
أخبرني عن ذلك
Make yourself comfortable and don't be shy.
ولا تخجلني
All right. I'll keep it in mind.
حسنًا، سأضع الأمر في الاعتبار
Your Highness,
صاحبة السمو
whatever you want to do,
كل ما تريد القيام به
let me know in the first place.
أعلميني في المقام الأول
♪Time doesn't last till the end♪
♪ لا يستمر الوقت حتى النهاية ♪
♪Instantly everything flashes back♪
♪ في الحال يطفح كل شيء في الخلف ♪
♪As the sky sighs, the stars twinkle♪
♪ مع تغير السماء، تشتهي النجوم ♪
♪I can't forget how you look at me♪
♪ لا أستطيع نسيان كيف تنظر إليّ ♪
Stay alert, everybody.
ابق في حالة تأهب جميعًا
♪And I don't fear instant disappearance♪
♪ ولا أخشى الاختفاء الفوري ♪
♪I close my eyes and make a wish♪
♪ أغمضت عينيّ وأتمنى أمنية ♪
♪Love is everything I'd wish for♪
الحب هو كل ما أتمنى ♪
He left so unexpectedly.
غادر بغتة
She changed so quickly.
تغيرت بسرعة كبيرة
(The House of Breeze)
(بيت بريز)
Your Grace,
غريسك
the South Prince had an invitation sent.
كان الأمير الجنوب قد أرسل دعوة
The South Prince?
الأمير الجنوبي؟
(Invitation)
(دعوة)
Whose letter is it?
من هي رسالتها؟
"Greetings, Your Grace.
"تحياتي يا غرامك
I hear you love sheep and cows.
سمعت أنك تحبين الأغنام والبقر
I have a very cute little pig.
لديّ خنزير صغير ظريف جدًا
It's quite adorable.
إنها جميلة جدًا
So, I'd like to invite you to see it."
لذا أود أن أدعوك لرؤية ذلك "
The South Prince?
الأمير الجنوبي؟
Pig?
أيها الخنزير؟
This prince is so different.
هذا الأمير مختلف جدًا
He knew you loved sheep and cows,
كان يعرف أنك تحب الأغنام والبقر
but he still mentioned his pig.
لكنه ذكر الخنزير الخاص به
I wonder how his pig may taste better,
أتساءل كيف مذاقه أفضل
roasted or stewed.
محمصة أو مخترقة
Stewed, I think.
حكيم، أعتقد
I won't go.
لن أذهب
He stole the account book.
سرق دفتر الحساب
- I'll go, then. - No. No one can go.
- سأذهب إذًا - لا، لا يمكن لأحد أن يذهب
(Benign and Benevolent)
(خير وخير)
(Shall I write him a letter?)
(هل أكتب له رسالة؟)
(But what can I write in the letter?)
(ولكن ما الذي يمكنني الكتابة فيه؟)
Hey, Your Grace.
اسمع يا غريزك
Bad news.
أخبار سيئة
The Great Consort will hold a feast for her juniors.
ستكون للقرينة العظيمة وليمة لصغار السن
You're invited to the palace.
أنت مدعو إلى القصر
The palace carriage is waiting out there.
عربة القصر تنتظر الخروج هناك
Butler Wen asked you to get dressed up and go.
طلب منك بتلر وين أن تتأنقي وتذهبي
To the palace?
إلى القصر؟
(Benign and Benevolent)
(خير وخير)
Qianqian.
تشيان
Do I look like my eldest sister?
هل أبدو مثل أختي الأكبر؟
Mostly, in terms of posture.
في الغالب، من حيث الموقف
But in terms of tone,
ولكن من حيث النغمة
you need to sound calmer.
يجب أن تبدو أكثر هدوءا
Then, you'll look more like her.
إذن، ستبدو أكثر مثلها
All right.
حسنًا
Your dress looks great.
ثوبك يبدو رائعًا
Yeah, doesn't it?
نعم، أليس كذلك؟
Look. That's the future North Princess Consort.
انظر هذا هو قرين الأميرة الشمالية المستقبلية
She's pretty.
إنها جميلة
Sadly, she's from Dongyu.
للأسف، إنها من دونغيو
Yeah, indeed.
نعم، بالفعل
That's too bad.
هذا مؤسف للغاية
The North Prince is charming, after all.
الأمير الشمالي ساحر، بعد كل شيء
(What's the problem with Dongyu girls?)
(ما المشكلة مع فتيات دونغيو؟)
(You think we want to be married here?)
(أتظن أننا نريد أن نتزوج هنا)
If she wasn't a princess,
إذا لم تكن أميرةً
what kind of man would like her?
أي نوع من الرجال ترغب فيها؟
Oh, the Princess of Dongyu is also here.
أميرة دونغ يو هنا أيضًا
Such a rare visitor.
زائر نادرة كهذه
Look at her.
انظري إليها
Why is she so perky?
لماذا هي بارعة جدًا؟
Your Grace, why do you not talk to anyone?
غراسك، لماذا لا تتحدث إلى أحد؟
Do you look down on me
هل تقلل من شأني
or do your people despise Beishuo people?
أم أن شعبك يكره شعب بيشو؟
- Yeah. - That's right.
- نعم - هذا صحيح
Dongyu is a deserted small state.
دونغيو مقاطعة صغيرة مهجورة
How can she look down our state?
كيف يمكن أن تقلل من شأن مقاطعتنا؟
Yeah.
نعم
She's a mere princess for marriage.
إنها مجرد أميرة للزواج
How can she be so perky?
كيف يمكن أن تكون مرحة جدًا؟
She doesn't even talk.
إنها لا تتكلم حتى
Dongyu isn't a deserted small state.
دونغيو ليس مقاطعة صغيرة مهجورة
Like your state,
مثل مقاطعتك
we have fortified cities,
لقد حصنا المدن
vast lands,
أراضي شاسعة
simple people,
أشخاص بسيطون
and strong troops.
والقوات القوية
You're shortsighted.
أنت قصيرة النظر
I won't bother with you, then.
لن أتكبد عناء معكم إذن
But please get to know clearly
لكن من فضلك تعرفوا بوضوح
before you say anything
قبل أن تقول أي شيء
in case you make a fool of yourselves.
في الحالة التي تجعل فيها المرء أحمق في حد ذاته
Who will actually laugh?
من سيضحك في الحقيقة؟
We're shortsighted,
نحن قصيرة النظر
but we won't marry our princess for peace.
لكننا لن نتزوج أميرتنا من أجل السلام
- Yeah. - That's right.
- نعم - هذا صحيح
When you're out of Dongyu,
عندما تخرج من دونغيو
you don't know what kind of life you'll live.
أنت لا تعرف أي نوع من الحياة ستعيشين
- Yeah. - That's right.
- نعم - هذا صحيح
Don't be so perky.
لا تكوني مرحة للغاية
- Let's ignore her.
- دعنا نتجاهلها
(If there was another way out,)
(إذا كانت هناك طريقة أخرى للخروج،)
(who would want to leave her hometown?)
(من قد يريد مغادرة مسكنها؟)
Your Grace, the Great Consort wants to talk to you.
غريسك، القرينة العظيمة تريد التحدث معك
Please come with me.
من فضلك تعال معي
Why does Her Royal Highness want to see me?
لماذا تريد صاحبة السمو الملكي رؤيتي؟
Her Royal Highness always cares about the North Prince,
صاحبة السمو الملكي دائما تهتم بالأمير الشمالي
so she wants to talk to you privately.
لذلك تريد التحدث إليك على انفراد
Come, please.
تعال، من فضلك
Why did Her Royal Highness invite her only?
لماذا دعوة الملكة الملكية لها فقط؟
Who cares?
من يهتم؟
It can't be anything good.
لا يمكن أن يكون جيدا
This way, Your Grace.
بهذا الطريق يا غرامك
Why is this place so dark?
لماذا هذا المكان مظلم جدا؟
Why are you locking me up?
لماذا تحتجزهم؟
Don't go!
لا تذهب!
Anybody out there?
أي فرد هناك؟
Her Royal Highness also invited the Princess of Dongyu, huh?
كما دعت أميرة دونغيو، هوه؟
Why isn't she here?
لماذا ليست هنا؟
Your Highness,
صاحبة السمو
Her Grace was summoned alone by Her Royal Highness.
استدعتها الملكة الملكية وحدها
Now, she's gone there.
الآن، إنها ذهبت إلى هناك
Zhou Zhixuan,
تشو تشيشيوان
don't go too far.
لا تذهب بعيدا
She's the North Prince's wife.
إنها زوجة الأمير الشمالي
What does she concern you?
ما الذي يهمك؟
Gao Luoyi,
قاو لويي
don't bother who I care about.
لا تزعج من أهتم
You must be jealous.
لا بد أن تشعري بالغيرة
Because I care about the Princess of Dongyu,
لأنني أهتم بأميرة دونغيو
right?
صحيح
I'm the Commandery Princess,
أنا الملكة الأميرة
the cousin of His Majesty,
ابن عم جلالة الإمبراطور
and the biological sister of the Lord of the South.
وأخت ملك الجنوب البيولوجية
Why would I be jealous
لماذا أشعر بالغيرة
of a princess from a deserted state?
من أميرة من مقاطعة مهجورة؟
You're not jealous of her.
أنت لا تغار منها
Then you must be admiring me.
إذن لا بد أنك مُعجبة بي
Or why would you care so much
أو لماذا تهتم إلى هذا الحد
about who I care for?
عمن أهتم؟
Zhou Zhixuan,
تشو تشيشيوان
you've always had an odd way of thinking.
لديك دائما طريقة غريبة في التفكير
But why are you even narcissistic when you grow up?
لكن لماذا تنتمين إلى النارسيس عندما تكبر؟
How can I possibly admire you?
كيف يمكنني أن أُعجب بك؟
The one I admire
الشخص الذي أحبه
has to be Shiyu.
يجب أن يكون شيو
You've never been as good as him.
لم تكن بمثل هذه البراعة
I wouldn't even give you a second look.
لن أعطيك نظرة ثانية حتى
Shiyu, Shiyu.
شييو
He was expelled to Liuzhou.
تم طرده إلى ليوتشو
You don't even know if he can come back alive.
أنت لا تعرف حتى إذا كان بإمكانه العودة أحياء
Don't be so sarcastic.
لا تسخر منه
You got him in this trouble.
أدخلته في هذه المتاعب
Gao Luoyi.
قاو لويي
- It's just you. - The Great Consort is here.
- إنها أنت فقط - القرينة العظيمة هنا
Take your seats.
خذ مقاعدك
Why isn't the Princess of Dongyu here?
لماذا ليست أميرة دونغيو هنا؟
Sorry, Your Royal Highness.
آسف يا صاحب السمو الملكي
Her Grace didn't feel very well
لم يكن شعورها جيدا
and she went back.
وعادت
How impolite!
كم هو غير مهذب!
Forget it.
انس الأمر
Let's get started.
دعنا نبدأ
(She didn't go see Her Royal Highness.)
(لم تذهب لرؤية صاحبة السمو الملكي)
(Weird.)
(ويرد)
(If she's away,)
(إذا عادت)
(I've come for nothing, then.)
(لقد جئت من أجل لا شيء، إذن)
Anybody out there?
أي أحد هناك؟
Open the door!
افتح الباب!
Anybody?
أي شخص؟
(Zhou Shiyu, if only you were here!)
(تشو شييو، لو كنت هنا فقط!)
(Pleasant and Harmonious)
(النعمة والوئام)
Come on, Linmu.
هيا يا لنمو
Her Grace has been in the palace for much of the day.
عرشها في القصر منذ فترة طويلة
Now, it's dark.
الآن، الظلام داكن
Why hasn’t she come back yet?
لماذا لم تعد بعد؟
When you're just away from Her Grace for half a day,
عندما تبعد فقط عن غريس لمدة نصف يوم
you've started to miss her.
بدأت تفتقدها
When you get married,
عندما تتزوج
you will be a wife
ستكون زوجة
who sticks to her husband, huh?
من يتمسك بزوجها، هوه؟
I'm not going to get married.
لن أتزوج
Her Grace saved my life.
أنقذت غريس حياتي
I'll stay with her all my life.
سأبقى معها طوال حياتي
Marry someone around her
اتزوجت شخصًا من حولها
and the problem will be solved.
وسيتم حل المشكلة
Don't waste your time arguing with me.
لا تضيع وقتك في الجدل معي
Send someone to the palace
أرسلوا شخصا ما إلى القصر
and find out what Her Grace is doing.
لمعرفة ما تفعله غريس
All right.
حسنًا
I'm on it.
أنا عليها
His Highness has some men in the palace.
سموه لديه بعض الرجال في القصر
You don't need to worry too much.
لا داعي للقلق كثيرا
Hurry, then.
هيا
Go faster. Go.
أسرع، هيا
There you are, Your Majesty.
ها أنت ذي يا صاحب الجلالة
I'll make you some tea.
سأعد لك بعض الشاي
Who are you?
من أنت؟
What "Your Majesty"? I'm not the empress.
ماذا؟ لست الإمبراطورة
Come and greet Her Majesty.
وتحياتي
- Greetings, Her Majesty.
- تحياتي يا صاحبة الجلالة
Don't kneel to me.
لا تركع لي
I'm really not the empress.
أنا لست الإمبراطورة حقًا
You're not the empress.
أنت لست الإمبراطورة
Finally, you're sober.
يا إلهي، أنت صاح
You're the emperor.
أنت الإمبراطور
The emperor is here to see us.
الإمبراطور هنا لرؤيتنا
- Long live Your Majesty.
- أتمنى أن تعيش لآلاف السنين - تعيش لآلاف السنين يا صاحب الجلالة
I should go.
يجب أن أذهب
You must not go.
يجب ألا تذهبي
You haven't seen what I prepared you.
لم تري ما أعددته لك
- Come on. - Let me go.
- هيا - دعني وشأني
Let go of her.
دعها وشأنها
I invited you over to see Piggy.
دعوتك لرؤية الأكولة
Why didn't you come?
لماذا لم تأتي؟
Naughty.
ابنة
Is it appropriate to say this now?
هل من المناسب قول هذا الآن؟
That's right.
هذا صحيح
Why do you not salute me?
لماذا لا تحياتي؟
Where are your manners?
أين أخلاقك؟
Forget it.
انس الأمر
Let go of her.
دعها وشأنها
I won't.
لن أفعل
You little poor thing,
أيها المسكين
how dare you disobey me?
كيف تجرؤ على عصبي؟
Are you sure you won't let her go?
هل أنت متأكدة من أنك لن تتركها تذهب؟
Yes.
نعم
I'm getting angry, then.
أنا غاضبة إذًا
Don't blame me for being rude.
لا تلوميني على تصرفاتي
See?
أرأيت؟
Without a smart prince like me,
بدون أمير ذكي مثلي
you wouldn't be saved, huh?
لن يتم إنقاذك، هوه؟
Yeah. Thanks.
نعم شكرًا
That's all?
هل هذا كل شيء
What else do you want?
ماذا تريد أيضًا؟
You think it was easy to get you out, huh?
هل تعتقد أنه كان من السهل الخروج لك يا هوه؟
You're lucky enough
أنت محظوظ بما فيه الكفاية
to have met me.
لأنني التقيت بي
And I was smart enough
وكنت ذكية بما فيه الكفاية
to hear something from Gao Luoyi.
للاستماع إلى شيء من قاو لويي
Otherwise, you wouldn't know
خلاف ذلك، لن تعرفي
how much longer you had to be locked up.
كم من الوقت كان عليك أن تُحتجزي
We're even, then.
تعادلنا إذًا
What do you mean?
ماذا تعني؟
Fine, you saved me for this once.
حسنًا، أنقذتني من أجل هذا مرة
Forget about the stealing thing
انسي أمر السرقة
and I'll let you go.
وسأتركك
Stealing?
السرقة؟
You sound really weird.
تبدين غريبةً جدًا
I saved your life.
لقد أنقذت حياتك
Instead of praising my courage,
بدلًا من الإشادة بشجاعتي
you wronged me for stealing something.
لقد ظيفتني لأنك سرقت شيئًا ما
Fine, fine.
حسنا، حسنا
Thank you, Your Highness.
شكرا لك يا صاحب السمو
I have nothing to pay for your kindness.
ليس لدي ما أدفع ثمن لطفك
I'll visit you another day and thank you.
سأزورك في يوم آخر وأشكر لك
That's more like it.
هذا يشبه كل شيء
Look how courageous I was.
انظري كم كنت شجاعة
I'm better than Zhou Shiyu, aren't I?
أنا أفضل من تشو شي يو، أليس كذلك؟
How about you break it off with him
ماذا عن أنك انفصلته معه
and marry me instead?
وتزوجني بدلا من ذلك؟
Now, I'm kind of your lifesaver.
الآن، أنا نوع من فترة حياتك
I'll barely allow you
لن أسمح لك كثيرا
to marry me in return.
للزواج مني في المقابل
That's too bad.
هذا سيء جدا
Zhou Shiyu didn't see
تشو شي يو لم تر
how I saved his girl today.
كيف أنقذت فتاته اليوم
If he saw that, he would be annoyed.
إذا رأى ذلك، فإنه سوف يزعجه
Oh, right.
بالمناسبة
I should write a letter to him.
يجب أن أكتب رسالة إليه
Wait for me.
انتظرني
(When I'm away,)
(عندما أكون في الخارج)
(is everything all right with you?)
(هل كل شيء على ما يرام معك؟)
♪I'll always be in love with you♪
♪ سأكون دائما في حبك ♪
♪Promising it'll last forever♪
♪ مؤشر على أنها ستدوم إلى الأبد ♪
♪As the breeze blows, the flower fades♪
♪ مع ضربات النسيم، تتلاشى الزهرة ♪
♪Leaving a wish to be fulfilled♪
♪ إنقاذ أمنية يتعين تحقيقها ♪
♪To have joy for the rest of its life♪
♪ للفخر لبقية حياتها ♪
♪I'll stay with you for thousands of years♪
♪ سأبقى معك بآلاف السنين ♪
♪Until we grow old together♪
♪ حتى نتقدم في السن معا ♪
♪As the breeze blows, the flower fades♪
♪ كما ضربات النسيم، تتلاشى الزهرة ♪
♪When I look back, you whisper♪
♪ عندما أنظر إلى الوراء، أنت أتذمر ♪
♪Then I wake up from the dream like how we met for the first time♪
♪ إذن أستيقظ من الحلم مثل الطريقة التي التقينا بها للمرة الأولى ♪
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو
a letter from the Capital City
رسالة من العاصمة
was delivered to the posthouse swiftly.
تم تسليمها إلى الحوزة بسرعة
(To Zhou Shiyu) (Can it be from Yueling?)
(إلى تشو شيو) (هل يمكن أن يكون من يويلينغ؟)
Zhou Shiyu,
تشو شيو
I, the courageous and charming prince,
أنا، الأمير الشجاع الساحر
and the Princess of Dongyu love each other now.
وأميرة دونغيو يحبان بعضهما البعض الآن
The other day, I saved her in the palace
في ذلك اليوم، أنقذتها في القصر
by getting her out of the deserted palace after she stayed there all night.
بإخراجها من القصر المهجور بعد أن بقيت هناك طوال الليل
Since then, she's been in love with me
منذ ذلك الحين، هي في حبي
and I love her, too.
أنا أحبها أيضًا
So, I'm writing to tell you this.
لذا أكتب لك لأخبرك بهذا
Hope you're wise enough
آمل أن تكون حكيما بما فيه الكفاية
to get scared off
للتخلص من الخوف
and give up soon.
بالاستسلام قريبا
Or you would be the first man in our family
أم أنك أول رجل في عائلتنا
to lose his engagement.
لفقدان خطبته
The deserted palace?
القصر المهجور؟
Nie Chen, send someone back to the Capital City.
ني تشن، أعاد شخصا إلى العاصمة
I need to know whatever happened to Yueling.
يجب أن أعرف ما حدث ليوينغ
Yes. I'm on it.
نعم، أنا على قائمة المرشحين
Your Highness, the team is ready.
صاحب السمو، الفريق مستعد
We can leave in a moment.
يمكننا المغادرة بعد قليل
But Mr. Shi Xuan is unacclimatized.
لكن السيد شي
He's resting at our last stop.
إنه يرتاح في التوقف الأخير
Don't we wait for him?
ألا ننتظره؟
Liuzhou has been in disaster for a long time.
لقد كانت ليوتشو في كارثة لفترة طويلة
People there complain with discontent.
الناس هناك يشتكون بالاستياء
The situation is terrible.
الوضع مريع
No time can be wasted.
لا يمكن إضاعة وقت
The Minister of Revenue is weak.
وزير الإيرادات ضعيف
Let him travel behind us.
دعه يسافر خلفنا
Yes.
نعم
When Zhou Shiyu reads the letter,
عندما يقرأ شو الرسالة
he'll be infuriated.
سيتم غضبه
Am I right, Piggy?
هل أنا محقة أيها الأكولة؟
Do you think Piggy
هل تظن الأكولة
can understand His Highness?
يمكن أن يفهم سموه؟
His Highness keeps talking to it.
الأمير يتحدث إليه باستمرار
Look how much you've eaten.
انظري كم أكلت
Indeed,
بالفعل
Piggy behaves better in His Highness's hands.
الأكولة تتصرف بشكل أفضل في أيدي سموه
- When you're in a good mood, - Right, huh?
- عندما تكون في مزاج جيد - صحيح، أهي؟
you also have a good appetite,
لديك شهية جيدة أيضًا
right?
صحيح
- Your Highness. - Good pig.
- صاحب السمو - خنزير جيد
The North Prince has gone to Liuzhou.
لقد ذهب الأمير الشمالي إلى ليوتشو
Why do you not feel anxious?
لماذا لا تشعر بالقلق؟
What if he does something great to atone for his crime?
ماذا لو فعل شيئًا رائعًا للتكفير عن جريمته؟
Why would I be anxious?
لماذا أشعر بالقلق؟
Zhou Shiyu has gone there for hardships.
تشو شيوي ذهب إلى هناك للصعوبات
What does "atoning for crime" mean?
ماذا يعني "الكرات للجريمة"؟
One has to commit a crime
يجب على المرء ارتكاب جريمة
before he can atone for it.
قبل أن يكفر عن ذلك
What great things can he do?
ما هي الأشياء العظيمة التي يمكنه القيام بها؟
If he takes good care of the disaster relief
إذا كان يهتم جيدا بالإغاثة في حالات الكوارث
and returns successfully,
والعودة بنجاح
I'm afraid
أنا أخشى أنه
he'll only be meritorious.
سيكون جديرا فقط
Are you saying
هل تقصد أنه
he'll steal my thunder again?
سوف يسرق رقيقي مرة أخرى؟
That's right, Your Highness.
هذا صحيح يا صاحب السمو
But I've just got closer to the Princess of Dongyu.
لكنني اقترب من أميرة دونغيو
Xu, what do you think I should do?
شو، ماذا رأيك يجب أن أفعل؟
Don't panic, Your Highness.
لا تستعجل يا صاحب السمو
If the North Prince fails his duty
إذا فشل الأمير الشمالي في واجبه
and can't return successfully,
ولا يستطيع العودة بنجاح
he won't be meritorious.
لن يكون جديرا بالجدارة
I asked you
طلبت منك
to tell the chefs to make some chicken soup for His Highness. Did you?
مطالبة الطهاة بصنع بعض حساء الدجاج لسموه، أليس كذلك؟
- That's right. - I did.
- هذا صحيح - بل فعلت
You care so much for His Highness.
أنت تهتم كثيرا بسموه
Of course.
بالطبع
(Liuzhou)
(ليوتشو)
Next.
التالي
Grandpa, wake up.
استيقظ يا جدتي
Wake up for some porridge.
استيقظ لبعض العصيدة
Grandpa, what's wrong with you?
جدتي ما خطبك؟
Grandpa.
جددا
Your Highness, this is the Relief Service Center in Liuzhou.
صاحب السمو، هذا هو مركز خدمات الإغاثة في ليوتشو
Let's go have a look.
دعنا نذهب ونلق نظرة
Yes.
نعم
Evil official, give us some food.
أيها المسؤول الأشرار، أعطنا بعض الطعام
We want porridge instead of water.
نريد عصيدة بدلا من المياه
- Yeah. - That's right.
- نعم - هذا صحيح
It's only the rice soup.
إنه فقط حساء الأرز
Why is there not even a single grain in it?
لماذا لا توجد حبوب واحدة فيها؟
No rice in the soup.
لا أرز في الحساء
What are you talking about?
عمّ تتحدث؟
You're so unruly!
أنت جامح جدًا!
How dare you gather and make trouble?
كيف تجرئين على التجمع وإثارة المتاعب؟
Somebody.
شخص ما
Come and catch
تعال وأقبض
these two troublemakers!
هذين المشاغبين!
- Yes. - Stop.
- نعم - توقف
Who are you, gentleman?
من أنت، أيها السيد؟
Why is there only rice soup?
لماذا لا يوجد سوى حساء الأرز؟
You have no idea, sir.
لا فكرة لديك يا سيدي
These people
هؤلاء الناس
come for food with their families every day.
يأتون من أجل الطعام مع عائلاتهم كل يوم
The government granary has been empty.
كانت مخزن الحبوب الحكومي فارغةً
There's really...
لا يمكنني فعل شيء
There's really nothing I can do.
لا شيء يمكنني فعله
Nonsense, you evil official.
هراء، أنت المسؤول الأشرار
Terrible rice keepers like you
حراس الأرز الرهيب مثلك
have emptied the granary.
تم إفراغ مخزن الحبوب
That's right.
هذا صحيح
Life is good for you.
الحياة جيدة لك
You have rice every day.
لديك الأرز كل يوم
But we...
لكننا...
We can't even have any rice husks.
لا يمكننا الحصول على أي قشور أرز حتى
Stop slandering me.
كفّ عن التشهير بي
Do you have a death wish, huh?
هل تتمنى الموت يا هو؟
Do you...?
هل أنت...؟
How daring!
كيف تجرؤ!
How dare you be so rude to me?
كيف تجرؤ على أن تكون بهذه الوقاحة معي؟
Do you have a death wish?
هل تتمنى الموت؟
I think you actually have a death wish.
أظن أن لديك أمنية في الحقيقة
Take him away.
خذه بعيدًا
- He's taken away. - He's gone.
- لقد أُخذ - - لقد رحل
Rest assured, everybody.
كن مطمئنا جميعًا
I'll take care of this soon.
سأهتم بهذا قريبًا
- This is great.
- هذا رائع
Linmu,
لنمو
do you not have anything to do?
أليس لديك ما تفعلينه؟
Why do you come here every day?
لماذا تأتي إلى هنا كل يوم؟
My job is to protect Her Highness.
عملي هو حماية صاحبة السمو
Miss Qianqian, let me help you.
الآنسة تشيان، دعني أساعدك
No need.
لا حاجة
Then why do you always follow me?
إذن لماذا تتبعني دائما؟
Her Highness asked me
طلبت مني الملكة
to take orders from you.
أن أطلب منكم أوامر
So, who else can I follow?
لذلك، من يمكنني أن أتبعه غيري؟
Shh.
شياو لاي
Her Grace is writing something.
غراس يكتب شيئا
Keep your voice down.
حافظ على صوتك منخفضا
Don't annoy me.
لا تزعجني
Shh.
شيئًا
Let me help you. Come on.
دعني أساعدك هيا
(The Boost Healing Powder)
(مسحوق شفاء بو)
(I wonder how Shiyu is doing now.)
(أتساءل كيف حال شيو الآن)
(Has he totally recovered?)
(هل تعافى تماما؟)
Slow down.
تمهلي
Thank you.
شكرًا لك
Thank you so much.
شكرًا جزيلًا لك
Thanks.
شكرًا
- Thank you.
- شكرًا لك - شكرا لك
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو
we found many official grains in that grain keeper's house.
وجدنا العديد من الحبوب الرسمية في منزل حارس الحبوب ذاك
So, the people here told the truth.
لذلك، قال الناس هنا الحقيقة
Check all the grains
تحقق من جميع الحبوب
and make reasonable arrangements.
واتخاذ الترتيبات المعقولة
Make sure every refugee can get some porridge.
احرصي على أن يحصل كل لاجئ على بعض العصيدة
But more refugees are coming.
لكن المزيد من اللاجئين قادمون
I'm afraid
أنا خائف أنه
the remaining food can't last long.
لا يمكن للطعام المتبقي أن يستمر طويلا
Send someone to get Shi Xuan here.
أرسل شخصا ما للحصول على شيوان هنا
His grains can save lives.
يمكن لحبيباته أن تنقذ الأرواح
Yes. I'm on it.
نعم، أنا عليها
This is the place. Food is here.
هذا هي المكان، الطعام هنا
I'll get some first.
سأحصل على بعض الطعام أولًا
Nobody shall fight for it.
لا يجوز لأحد أن يقاتل من أجلها
Go, Nie Chen.
هيا، ني تشن
Come on, son.
هيا يا ابن
Don't snatch my food.
لا تنتزع طعامي
Don't snatch it.
لا تنتزع ذلك
Be careful, Your Highness!
كن حذرا يا صاحب السمو!
Someone's killing!
شخص ما يُقتل!
Run!
اركض!
♪Clouds slowly float across the sky♪
♪ الغيوم تطفو ببطء عبر السماء ♪
♪Telling what is awfully bothering♪
♪ وضع ما يزعج كثيرا ♪
♪Ceaseless, love lingers and lingers♪
♪ لا يتوقف، أحب الأمور المتبقية والدائمة ♪
♪You and I both know it♪
♪ أنا وأنت نعرف ذلك ♪
♪In this world, we stay side by side♪
♪ في هذا العالم، نبقى جنبا إلى جنب ♪
♪Watching the stars rise and fall♪
♪ مشاهدة النجوم ترتفع وتنخفض ♪
♪My eyes are red from missing you♪
♪ عيني أحمر من غيابكم ♪
♪Tonight, I hope the moonlight will♪
♪ ليلة، آمل أن يكون ضوء القمر ♪
♪Kiss your eyebrows♪
♪ قبلة حاجباك ♪
♪I'll always be in love with you♪
♪ سأكون دائمًا في حبك ♪
♪Promising it'll last forever♪
♪ مؤشر على أنها ستدوم إلى الأبد ♪
♪As the breeze blows, the flower fades♪
♪ مع ضربات النسيم، تتلاشى الزهرة ♪
♪Leaving a wish to be fulfilled♪
♪ إنقاذ أمنية يتعين تحقيقها ♪
♪To have joy for the rest of its life♪
♪ للفخر لبقية حياتها ♪
♪I'll stay with you for thousands of years♪
♪ سأبقى معك بآلاف السنين ♪
♪Until we grow old together♪
♪ حتى نتقدم في السن معا ♪
♪As the breeze blows, the flower fades♪
♪ كما ضربات النسيم، تتلاشى الزهرة ♪
♪When I look back, you whisper♪
♪ عندما أنظر إلى الوراء، أنت أتذمر ♪
♪Then I wake up from the dream♪
♪ إذن أستيقظ من الحلم ♪
♪Like how we met for the first time♪
♪ مثل كيفية التقينا للمرة الأولى ♪